nick-james.com 2007-05-12

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy 

Version dated 1st May 2004

**A. Nick-James.com & Power-Tech Associates Limited Privacy Policy.** Nick-James.com is committed to protecting your privacy, while providing you with the opportunity to receive products and services which enhance your business activities. 

This policy (?Privacy Policy?) describes the way in which we collect information from you when you use the service, and what we may use it for.

**B. What data do we collect from you?**

We collect data from you (?User Data?) in various ways: 

When you register as a subscriber to Nick-James.com, during the course of your subscription, When we request further information from you from time to time following on from registration. 

This data comprises of both billing information and some personal data about you, to which UK data protection laws apply. This Privacy Policy describes Nick-James.com's approach to fulfilling its obligations under those data protection laws.

**C. Our use of User Data.**

We will use User Data and we collect from you only in accordance with the following guidelines: 

i) **_To provide subscription to Nick-James.com._** We will use 'User Data' to provide and improve our subscription service, to enable our help desk to deal with any queries you may have about our service, to notify you about any change to our Service or our [Terms of Use](http://www.nick-james.com/public/73.cfm). ****  

ii) **_To send you information about our other products & services_**. From time to time, Nick-James.com, or third parties acting on our behalf, may wish to send you information about other products and services that we offer and we believe may be of interest to you, and we may use User Data for this purpose. If you decide now, or at any other time, that you do not wish to receive such information, please inform us by eMail at [nick@nick-james.com](mailto:nick@nick-james.com?subject=remove%20from%20mailing%20lists)

iii) _**To generate and deal in aggregate data**_. Nick-James.com may provide aggregate data about our Users, sales patterns and related usage information, to reputable third parties on a commercial basis, but this data shall not be in non-attributable form and will not enable any such third party to identify individual users or individual businesses.

iv) _**To provide data to third party providers**_. Nick-James.com may pass User Data to third party providers of products and services through the Service to enable them to provide services to you, and (where relevant) to facilitate billing. Nick-James.com does not as such authorise such third parties to use your User Data to market its own products and services, but you may have given such consent as part of your own relationship with the third party in question. 

v) **_To the Power-Tech Associates Limited group of companies._** Nick-James.com may make User Data available to other businesses in the Power-Tech group of companies, either for the fulfillment of Nick-James.com service or to enable them to provide you with information about products or services which they believe would be of interest to you.

**D. Legal Requirements.**

While it is unlikely, Nick-James.com may be required to disclose your User Data by a court or to comply with other legal requirements. We will use all reasonable endeavor to notify you before we do so, unless we are legally restricted from doing so. 

**E. No Commercial Disposal**.

To third Parties Nick-James.com shall not sell, rent, distribute or otherwise make User Data commercially available to any third party, except as described above. Or except with your permission. 

**F. Consent To Our Use**.

If you object to the use by Nick-James.com of your User Data in the manner described in section C above, please inform us by eMail at [nick@nick-james.com](mailto:nick@nick-james.com?subject=objection%20to%20section%20C%20Privacy%20Policy)

**G. Updating User Data Nick-James.com Holds About You**.

You can change or update the User Data that Nick-James.com holds about you at any time. You can do this by logging into the members area and selecting the link [Edit Member Profile](http://www.nick-james.com/members/department7.cfm) or by emailing us at: [nick@nick-james.com](mailto:nick@nick-james.com?subject=update%20of%20user%20details)

**H. Cookies**

Each time a subscriber logs into Nick-James.com, we store a temporary 'cookie' in the browser files of that subscriber's computer. This cookie is used during your online session to allow you free access to the Subscribers Area, without repeatedly requiring you to re-enter your user name and password. When you log off or leave the site, the cookies file is automatically removed.

**I. External Links**

In order to provide visitors with greater value, some of our pages may provide links to various third party websites. In no case is subscriber information or 'cookies' provided to the third party sites.

**J. Private Forums**

We provide our subscribers with a multi-tiered Discussion Forum that makes sharing information with other subscribers easy. To protect your privacy when posting or replying to messages in the message board, your personal information and email is not revealed.

NB. However, remember that any information you disclose in the message board areas can be read by all other subscribers, so exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

**K. Security**

We use a variety of security measures including encryption and authentication from Thawte to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of your personal information under our control. 

**L. Choice/Opt-In**

Our site gives users the opportunity to opt-in to receive communications from us. You can be assured that we never reveal, sell, or make available your email address to anyone for any purpose. This site also gives users options for removing their information from our database in order to stop receiving our communications. 

**M. Other**

If you have questions regarding our privacy policy, feel free to [contact us](http://www.nick-james.com/public/7.cfm).  

**N. Assent to Terms of Privacy Policy**.

By using Nick-James.com Service you acknowledge that you have read the terms of this Privacy Policy and that you agree to use User Data for the purposes set out above. Nick-James.com may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Nick-James.com will notify you through the Service of changes.
